Eric W. Lawson Arbitration Files 6366
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS), 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Item 4: Town of Irondequoit and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), 1994; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 4)
    June 6, 1994. Case number: 94-04405. Opinion and Award regarding seniority.
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS), 2001; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Federal Education Association and Departmen of Defense Dependents Schools, 2001; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 5)
    June 26, 2001. Case number 00-02814. Opinion and Award regarding living quarters allowance.
  - Item 2: Getting/Castle, Inc. and International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, Local 2312, 2001; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 5)
    September 24, 2001. Case number: 01-07458-8. Opinion and Award regarding termination.
  - Item 3: Federal Education Association and Departmen of Defense Dependents Schools, 2001; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 5)
    October 25, 2001. Case number: 00-02814. Motion for Directed Judgement: Decision regarding living quarters allowance.
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS), 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Federal Education Association and Departmen of Defense Dependents Schools, 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 6)
    May 10, 2002. Case number: 00-02814. Motion for Supplemental Findings and Award regarding living quarters allowance.
  - Item 2: Wyeth-Ayerst Pharmaceuticals and International Chemical Workers/UFCW, Local 95C, 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 6)
    December 7, 2002. Case number: 02-05235. Opinion and Award regarding termination.
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS), 2003; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Jamestown Metal Products and International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, Lodge 65, 2003; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 7)
    February 22, 2003. Case number: 02-15530. Opinion and Award regarding holiday pay.
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS), 2004; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Georgia Pacific Corporation and Paper, Allied-Industrial, Chemical and Energy Workers International Union (PACE), Locals 140 and 387, 2004; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 8)
    January 16, 2004. Case number: 03-08086-8. Opinion and Award regarding discharge.
  - Item 2: Compass Group USA and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), 2004; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 8)
    April 12, 2004. Case number: 04-00555. Opinion and Award regarding discharge.
  - Item 3: Laborer's Local 814 and WVU Hospitals, Inc., 2004; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 8)
    December 7, 2004. Case number: 04-54325. Opinion and Award regarding termination.
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS), 2007; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: US Department of the Interior, National Park Service, and Fraternal Order of Police First Federal Lodge 1-F, 2007; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 9)
    February 5, 2007. Case number: 051025-00427-7. Opinion and Decision regarding recycling through the FLETC.
  - Item 2: CA One Services, Inc. and UNITE HERE 1, 2007; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 9)
    March 24, 2007. Case number: 06-04390. Opinion and Decision regarding termination.
  - Item 3: Federal Bureau of Prisons, FCI, Beckley, West Virginia and Council of Prisons, Local 33 and 44, Beckley, West Virginia, 2007; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 9)
    December 14, 2007. Case number: 07-51912. Opinion and Decision regarding negotiated overtime procedures.
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS), 2008; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: New York National Guard and Association of Civilian Technicians (ACT), 2008; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 10)
    July 2008. Case number: 08-01105. Opinion and Decision regarding promotion.
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS), 2009; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Department of the Army, 10th Mountain Division, Fort Drum, and American Federation of Government Employees, Local 0400, 2009; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 11)
    July 14, 2009. Case number: 090109-52827-8. Opinion and Decision regarding official time for training.
  - Item 2: Severn Trent Environmental Services and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, AFSCME, 2009; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 11)
    December 4, 2009. Case number: 09-56425. Opinion and Decision regarding discharge.
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS), 2012; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Federal Bureau of Prisons and American Federation of Government Employees (AFGE), Federal Correctional Institution, Fort Dix, New Jersey, 2012; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 12)
    May 21, 2012. Case number: 11-52290-1. Opinion and Decision regarding master agreement violation.
- NYS Public Employment Relations Board (PERB), 2000; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: State of New York, Department of Correctional Services and New York State Correctional Officers and PBA, 2000; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 13)
    April 27, 2000. Case number: D99-077. Opinion and Award regarding misconduct.
  - Item 2: State of New York, Department of Correctional Services and New York State Correctional Officers and PBA, 2000; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 13)
    June 27, 2000. Case number: D99-024. Opinion and Award regarding $1000 fine, loss of leave, loss of swapping privileges.
  - Item 3: State of New York, Department of Correctional Services and New York State Correctional Officers and PBA, 2000; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 13)
    September 18, 2000. Case number: D99-024. Order Motion to Amend regarding $1000 fine, loss of leave, loss of swapping privileges.
- NYS Public Employment Relations Board (PERB), 2001; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: State of New York and Council 82, AFSCME, New York State Law Enforcement Employees Union, 2001; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 14)
    May 30, 2001. Case number: D200-200. Opinion and Award regarding termination.
  - Item 2: Niagara Falls Housing Authority and Council 66, Local 2442, AFSCME, 2001; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 14)
    November 6, 2001. Case number: A200-639. Opinion and Award regarding written reprimands.
- NYS Public Employment Relations Board (PERB), 2003; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: State of New York, Department of Correctional Services and New York State Correctional Officers and PBA, 2003; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 15)
    January 15, 2003. Case number: D201-196. Opinion and Award regarding termination.
  - Item 2: Town of Evans, NY, and Evans Police Benevolent Association, 2003; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 15)
    February 25, 2003. Case numbers: IA990-219 and M90-024. Opinion and Award regarding procedural issues.
  - Item 3: Niagara County and Niagara County Deputy Sheriff's PBA, 2003; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 15)
    August 25, 2003. Case number: A2002-395. Opinion and Award regarding court appearance notices.
- NYS Public Employment Relations Board (PERB), 2004; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Oneida County, and Oneida County Sheriff's Office, and Oneida County Sheriff's Employees, Local 1249, 2004; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 16)
    September 27, 2004. Case number: A2002-444. Opinion and Award regarding abuse of sick time.
  - Item 2: Geneseo Central School District and Geneseo Central School Faculty Association, 2004; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 16)
    December 21, 2004. Case number: A2044-120. Opinion and Award regarding denial of tenure.
  - Item 3: City of Rensselear, NY, and Professional Firefighters, Fire Drivers Association, Local 2643, IAFF, 2004; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 16)
    December 31, 2004. Case number: A2004-032. Opinion and Award regarding retirement pay-out.
- NYS Public Employment Relations Board (PERB), 2005; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: City of Jamestown and Council 66, Local 418, AFSCME, 2005; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 17)
    January 2, 2005. Case number: A2004-048. Opinion and Award regarding placement on wage schedule.
  - Item 2: Schalmont Central School District and Schalmont School Related Professionals Association, 2005; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 17)
    June 6, 2005. Case number: A2004-361. Opinion and Award regarding longevity pay.
  - Item 3: Schalmont Central School District and Schalmont School Related Professionals Association, 2005; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 17)
    June 6, 2005. Case number: A2004-361. Opinion and Award regarding longevity pay. Copy 2.
  - Item 4: Village of Endicott and Endicott Police Benevolent Association (PBA), 2005; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 17)
    October 20, 2005. Case number: A2005-078. Opinion and Award regarding stand-by and/or call-out time.
- NYS Public Employment Relations Board (PERB), 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: City of Plattsburgh, NY, and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 1249., 2006; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 18)
    April 8, 2006. Case number: A2005-176. Opinion and Award regarding promotions and transfers.
  - Item 2: Albany Housing Authority and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 801, 2007; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 18)
    December 20, 2007. Case number: A2007-015. Motion to Find that the Arbitrator Lacks the Authority to Decide the Matter regarding discipline/discharge.
  - Item 3: County of Greene and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, AFSCME, 2008; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 18)
    February 21, 2008. Case number: A2007-118. Opinion and Decision regarding termination.
- NYS Public Employment Relations Board (PERB), 2009; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: City of Plattsburgh, NY, and Council 66, Local 788, AFSCME, 2009; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 19)
    January 12, 2009. Case number: A2008-054. Opinion and Decision regarding custodial worker position.
  - Item 2: County of Saratoga and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, AFSCME, 2009; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 19)
    February 13, 2009. Case number: A2007-471. Opinion and Decision regarding descipline.
  - Item 3: Town of Brunswick and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, AFSCME, 2009; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 19)
    September 10, 2009. Case number: A2008-361. Opinion and Decision regarding vacation accruals.
- NYS Public Employment Relations Board (PERB), 2010; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: South Colonie Central School District and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, AFSCME, 2010; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 20)
    May 20, 2010. Case number: A2009-204. Opinion and Decision regarding opt-out insurance program.
  - Item 2: County of Albany and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 801, 2010; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 20)
    November 12, 2010. Case number: A2009-501. Opinion and Decision regarding parking pass.
- NYS Public Employment Relations Board (PERB), 2011; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: County of Albany and Council 82, Local 775, Albany County Sheriff's Security and Law Enforcement Employees, 2011; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 21)
    June 25, 2011. Case number: A2010-324. Opinion and Decision regarding disciplinary action.
  - Item 2: County of Franklin and United Public Service Employees Union (UPSEU), 2011; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 21)
    July 5, 2011. Case number: A2010-329. Opinion and Decision regarding discharge.
  - Item 3: Albany Housing Authority and Public Employees Federation (PEF), Housing Unit, 2011; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 21)
    July 21, 2011. Case number: A2010-494. Opinion and Decision regarding demotion
  - Item 4: Schenectady County Sheriff and Coundil 82, Local 3874, AFSCME, Schenectady County Sheriff's Benevolent Association, 2011; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 21)
    October 21, 2011. Case number: A2010-619. Opinion and Decision regarding discipline.
- NYS Public Employment Relations Board (PERB), 2012; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: City of Glens Falls, NY, and Glens Falls Police Benevolent Association, 2012; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 1)
    September 28, 2012. Case number: A2011-028. Opinion and Decision regarding salary and health insurance.
  - Item 2: Finch Paper and Empire State Millwrights, Local 1163, 2012; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 1)
    October 22, 2012. Case number: A2012-076. Opinion and Decision regarding Sunday day crew size.
- NYS Public Employment Relations Board (PERB), 2013; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: County of Onondaga and Deputy Sheriffs' Benevolent Association of Onondaga County, 2013; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 2)
    April 29, 2013. Case number: A2012-239. Opinion and Decision regarding disciplinary charges.
  - Item 2: City of Utica and John J. Creedon Police Benevolent Association, 2013; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 2)
    July 22, 2013. Case number: A2012-414. Opinion and Decision regarding disciplinary charges.
- NYS State Education Department (SED), 1987-1997 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Buffalo Board of Education, District Committee on Special Education, and L. and W. M., 1987; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 3)
    August 19, 1987. Findings of Fact and Decision regarding placement of children with handicapping conditions.
  - Item 2: New York City Board of Education, Community School District no.27, and United Federation of Teachers (UFT), 1994; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 3)
    April 12, 1994. Motion to Dismiss regarding corporal punishment.
  - Item 3: Office of Vocational and Educational Services for Individuals with Disabilities (VESID) and Suzanne Behun, 1994; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 3)
    July 3, 1994. Opinion and Decision regarding application for tuition and other support to attend college.
  - Item 4: Buffalo City School District and MS A. N., Parent of Student J. N., 1996; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 3)
    July 2, 1996. Opinion and Decision regarding classification as mentally retarded.
  - Item 5: State of New York, New York State School for the Blind and C. and E. R., Parents of K. R., 1997; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 3)
    January 6, 1997. Findings of Fact and Recommendation regarding placement of student.
- NYS State Education Department (SED), 2000; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Board of Education of the City of New York and Tenured School Employee, 2000; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 4)
    December 15, 2000. Case number: 4021. Findings of Fact and Decision regarding termination.
- NYS State Education Department (SED), 2001; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Board of Education of the Marlboro Central School and Tenured School Employee, 2001; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 5)
    March 1, 2001. Case number: 3947. Findings of Fact and Decision regarding conduct unbecoming a teacher and insubordination.
  - Item 2: Board of Education of the City of New York and Tenured School Employee, 2001; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 5)
    March 8, 2001. Case number: 4021. Findings of Fact and Decision regarding termination.
  - Item 3: Board of Education of the Victor Central School District and Tenured School Employee, 2001; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 5)
    March 23, 2001. Case number: 4033. Findings of Fact and Decision regarding conduct unbecoming a teacher and insubordination.
  - Item 4: Jason Keicher and Office of Vocational and Educational Services for Individuals with Disabilities (VESID), 2001; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 5)
    April 10, 2001. Opinion and Award regarding eligibility for benefits.
  - Item 5: Daniel Calciano and Office of Vocational and Educational Services for Individuals with Disabilities (VESID), 2001; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 5)
    April 28, 2001. Opinion and Award regarding relocation compensation.
  - Item 6: Springville Griffith Institute Central School District and D. R. Parent of R. R., 2001; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 5)
    June 7, 2001. Findings of Fact and Recommendation regarding payment for copying school records.
  - Item 7: Baldwin Union Free School District, County of Nassau, and Tenured School Employee, 2001; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 5)
    October 20, 2001. Case number: 3930. Findings of Fact and Decision regarding discipline.
- NYS State Education Department (SED), 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: New York City Board of Education and Tenured School Employee, 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 6)
    January 18, 2002. Case number: 4346. Opinion and Decision regarding conduct unbecoming a teacher, corporal punishment, and insubordination.
  - Item 2: New York City Board of Education and Tenured School Employee, 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 6)
    August 14, 2002. Case number: 4352. Opinion and Decision regarding termination.
  - Item 3: New York City Board of Education and Tenured School Employee, 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 6)
    October 10, 2002. Case number: 4468. Motions to Dismiss All Specifications and Specification 12 and to Particularize and Produce Decision regarding criminal misconduct.
  - Item 4: Kingston City School District and Tenured School Employee, 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 6)
    October 9, 2002. Case number: 4404. Opinion and Decision regarding discharge.
  - Item 5: New York City Board of Education and Tenured School Employee, 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 6)
    November 15, 2002. Case number: 4155. Opinion and Decision regarding termination.
  - Item 6: New York City Board of Education and Tenured School Employee, 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 6)
    November 15, 2002. Case number: 4791. Opinion and Decision regarding termination.
- NYS State Education Department (SED), 2003; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: E. C. and Hudson Falls Central School District, 2004; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 7)
    December 29, 2003. Office of Vocational and Educational Services for Individuals with Disabilities (VESID). Motion for Summary Judgment Dismissing Petitioner's Claims and Application to Withdraw the Demand for a Hearing Without Prejudice regarding right
  - Item 1: New York City Board of Education and Tenured School Employee, 2003; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 7)
    May 7, 2003. Case number 4443. Opinion and Decision regarding conduct unbecoming a teacher, conduct prejudicial to good order.
  - Item 2: New York City Board of Education and Tenured School Employee, 2004; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 7)
    April 2, 2004. Case number: 4740. Motion for Mistrial Order.
  - Item 2: A. O'H. Parent of E. C. and Hudson Falls Central School District, 2003; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 7)
    December 29, 2003. Office of Vocational and Educational Services for Individuals with Disabilities (VESID). Omnibus Motions regarding right
  - Item 3: New York City Board of Education and Tenured School Employee, 2004; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 7)
    July 5, 2004. Case number: 4815. Opinion and Decision regarding discharge.
  - Item 4: New York City Board of Education and Tenured School Employee, 2004; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 7)
    September 20, 2004. Case number: 4844. Opinion and Decision regarding discharge.
  - Item 5: New York City Board of Education and Tenured School Employee, 2004; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 7)
    November 3, 2004. Case number: 4937. Opinion and Decision regarding termination.
- NYS State Education Department (SED), 2004; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 8)
- NYS State Education Department (SED), 2005; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: New York City Board of Education, Community School District no.20, and Tenured School Employee, 2005; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 9)
    February 22, 2005. Case number: 5034. Opinion and Decision regarding termination.
  - Item 2: New York City Board of Education and Tenured School Employee, 2005; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 9)
    April 30, 2005. Case number: 5013. Opinion and Decision regarding termination.
  - Item 3: New York City Board of Education and Tenured School Employee, 2005; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 9)
    June 15, 2005. Case number: 5051. Opinion and Decision regarding corporal punishment, conduct unbecoming a teacher, and neglect of duties.
  - Item 4: New York City Board of Education and Tenured School Employee, 2005; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 9)
    July 1, 2005. Case number: 5129. Opinion and Decision regarding termination.
- NYS State Education Department (SED), 2006; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: New York City Board of Education and Tenured School Employee, 2006; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 10)
    August 23, 2006. Case number: 5234. Opinion and Decision regarding incompetence, insubordination, conduct unbecoming a teacher, and neglect of duties.
  - Item 2: New York City Board of Education and Tenured School Employee, 2006; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 10)
    November 4, 2006. Case number: 5282. Opinion and Decision regarding inappropriate behavior, misconduct, and conduct unbecoming a teacher.
- NYS State Education Department (SED), 2007; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: New York City Board of Education and Tenured School Employee, 2007; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 11)
    January 12, 2007. Case number: 5268. Opinion and Decision regarding excessive absenteeism, insubordination, misconduct, and neglect of duty.
  - Item 2: New York City Board of Education and Tenured School Employee, 2007; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 11)
    March 12, 2007. Case number: 5711. Opinion and Decision regarding misconduct, conduct unbecoming a teacher, and neglect of duty.
  - Item 3: New York City Board of Education and Tenured School Employee, 2007; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 11)
    May 11, 2007. Case number: 4456. Opinion and Decision regarding theft of services and insubordination.
  - Item 4: New York City Board of Education and Tenured School Employee, 2007; Arbitration Case (Box 3, Folder 11)
    August 27, 2007. Case number: 5348. Opinion and Decision regarding corporal punishment and neglect of duty.
- NYS State Education Department (SED), 2008; Arbitration Case (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Guilderland Central School District and Tenured School Employee, 2008; Arbitration Case (Box 4, Folder 1)
    November 5, 2008. Case number: 8125. Opinion and Deicision regarding incompetence, neglect of duty, disability, and insubordintion.
- NYS State Education Department (SED), Arbitration Case (Box 4, Folder 2)
  No Date
  - Item 1: New York City Board of Education and Tenured School Employee, Arbitration Case (Box 4, Folder 2)
    No date. Case number: 2622. Findings of Fact and Recommendations regarding misconduct.
  - Item 2: Board of Education of the Lansing Central School District and Tenures School Employee, Arbitration Case (Box 4, Folder 2)
    No date. Case number: 3029. Findings of Fact and Decision regarding conduct unbecoming a teacher, misconduct, and insubordination.
- Miscellaneous, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Chevrolet Motor Division and Customer, 1985; Arbitration Case (Box 4, Folder 3)
    March 16, 1985. Better Business Bureau of Western New York case number: 1 0172161. Opinion and Award regarding vehicle repairs.
  - Item 2: Buffalo Municipal Housing Authority and stationary engineer, 1986; Arbitration Case (Box 4, Folder 3)
    June 11, 1986. Findings and Recommendations regarding discipline and discharge.
  - Item 3: Abbot, Tills, and Knapp and Client, 1987; Arbitration Case (Box 4, Folder 3)